theslingshot.com 2011-12-08

# Slingshot

## privacy policy

Last updated 12/09/2010

theSlingshot.com is a collaborative intelligence platform. As such, it is predicated on the idea of sharing the intelligence of interesting content that is viewed among theSlingshot community for the benefit of all theSlingshot users. We collect the following data through your use of our service:

  * Any information you submitted while signing up for the service (including name, email, etc).
  * Your submitted articles, pictures and the documents with which they were associated.
  * Your clicks on content, recommendations of content and sponsored recommendations and the documents with which they were associated
  * IP address and an associated estimate of your geographic location, referring URL's, browser and OS and other information normally passed in HTTP requests.
  * Information about your engagement with web pages you've read where theSlingshot is installed, including time spent on the page, how you reached the page, and the type of content of the page

As part of theSlingshot service, your reporting on documents may be shared publicly and associated to the username you chose when signing up for the service. In addition, if you register on the site, your reporting and web page browsing history will be associated with the registration and personal data you provide and we will use that information to provide you with more targeted recommendations. However, any personally identifiable data you provide or that we collect about you will not be shared with 3rd parties (other than our service providers), unless required by law.

We use small text files stored on your web browser (otherwise known as cookies) for the purpose of better tailoring recommendations of content and sponsored recommendations of content to your preferences over time. We also use them in order to keep you logged in to theSlingshot service if you register with us. These cookies may include a unique anonymous identifier along with information about the particular type of content in which you have shown interest. We may use your web browsing information to try to show you specific recommendations of content and sponsored recommendations of content that we think will be of particular interest to you. We may combine information about your web browsing with those of other people who see theSlingshot in order to share trend information-always in aggregate and anonymously-- with 3rd parties. For instance, we may use it as part of an aggregated number to tell a prospective sponsor how many people in theSlingshot network visit Sports web sites each month.

If you click on a theSlingshot sponsored recommendation, the advertiser sponsoring the recommendation may cookie your web browser as well, in which case you will be subject to their privacy policy. Please note that you are subject to the privacy policies of each site you visit - if theSlingshot is installed on that site, you are subject both to our privacy policy and the policy of the web site owner. If you click on a theSlingshot link to visit a site where theSlingshot is not installed, you are subject only to that site's privacy policy while visiting that site, and not to ours.

  * We may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time and you should check back here periodically to see if has been updated. We will always show the latest modification date of the policy at the top of the page so you can tell when it has last been altered
  * We maintain tight controls over all the data we collect, retaining it in firewalled and secured databases with strictly limited & controlled access rights, to ensure it is secure
  * Our Privacy Policy only applies to online data collection since we only operate online
  * theSlingshot does not knowingly collect personal identifiable information from people under 13 years old and we ask people in our Terms of Use not to register with us and not to submit personal information if they are under 18.

If the privacy of your clicks on content, or the pages you visit is a concern for you, we urge you to do the following:

  * Choose a username that's not easily associated with you.
  * Do NOT click any recommendation or sponsored recommendation you do not want to be associated with.
  * Opt out of theSlingshot personalization tracking.

**Opt out of theSlingshot personalization tracking:**

When you opt out of theSlingshot’s personalization tracking, we will no longer use information about the pages you visit to tailor our recommendations of content and sponsored recommendations of content to your interests. We will still use information about documents you have clicked on to provide you better recommendations and sponsored recommendations - if you do not want us to use rating data or click data, please do not click on documents from our network. Also, please note:

**Opting out of theSlingshot personalization tracking does not mean you will no longer receive recommendations of content or sponsored recommendations of content from theSlingshot.** It does mean that the recommendations of content and sponsored recommendations of content we serve you will not be personalized based on pages you read in theSlingshot network. You will likely receive less benefit from theSlingshot system since our recommendations will not be as well tailored to your interests.

**We cookie you in order to prevent personalization tracking.** When you opt out of theSlingshot personalization tracking, we will cookie your computer with a special theSlingshot cookie that informs our servers not to record information about the pages you're visiting. If you browse the web from several computers, you will need to opt out from each computer to ensure that we prevent personalization tracking on all of them. For the same reason, if you buy a new computer, change web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform this opt-out task again.
